hi everybody welcome back to the channel
and today we're going to make haand
dar's strawberry cheesecake for the
second time in 2
days here is the bulk part of the ice
cream I made it
yesterday and I had audio problems with
every part of the recording so we're
making it again
it's a flavor that is very popular both
in the UK and North America and from
what you can tell pretty much everywhere
it's available it's a cheesecake base
with a strawberry
swirled through it and cheesecake
crumb pieces
throughout so that's what we're going to
do we're going to start with the base
and then work on to the other parts
after that so the
base let's get the pan out
and way what we
need into it nice and simple I don't
even know what it is we
need you think I would have figured that
out now doing it a second time around
but hey here we go so we need cream milk
and everything else is
there
cream
milk good stuff okay so we're going to
go
[Music]
g of
cream
125 of cream cheese yeah 500 of
milk
500 of milk
okay put these
away and to that we are going to add 125
G of cream cheese I think I got some
left how much
have how much have we got
left 30
92 so we got 90 G here so let's use
that we're going to cut this up into
little small cubes makes it easier to
melt so what do we say 125
G splash splash splash 125 G of cream
cheese I'll put the fat percentage of
this cream cheese in the description so
then you can calculate use an ice cream
calculator
nice and to that we're going to add our
sugars and skin milk powder cream cheese
on my
hands take those
off what have we
got 160 g of
sugar for this part yeah how much do we
want we want 40 G of dextr not enough
get the
other not in the
bag anytime you like come
on was enough there we go
nice and so let's put that in
here we're going to just leave a little
bit left over like
that
we're going to use our little baby
scales
to weigh out some
stabilizer heartshaped spoon
look got these in
Italy many years
ago we're going to go for not a lot
because this is quite a high fat
recipe
so just one G it's actually 1 one
G and then we're going to take our
little
[Applause]
whisk mix that and
nicely put all that in there now let
just our skin milk
powder two things dirty skin milk powder
let's turn that where is it we need 65 G
probably don't need 65 G to be fair but
we want this to be really
creamy
luxurious
cheesecake ice cream so we're going to
do everything we
can to make it that
[Applause]
way there we go
okay
now we are going
to get this on hob and get everything
brought up to temperature make sure the
cream cheese is completely melted make
sure the stabilizer is brought up to
temperature and go from
there good whilst that base is just
slowly warming
up just agitate it a little bit at the
start we're going to get our
strawberries
prepared I want to use the same pan cuz
I don't want to wash loads of things up
what you can do is prepare your
ingredients once that's up pour it in a
bowl you'll see we need our
strawberries we're going to use this
entire pack it's like 490
G which is a really weird pack size
but and we're going
to just cap them
we don't want any green in
there he's a nice ripe strawberries they
getting to the end of their life
strawberries now over here obviously
they're imported from I think
Mexico whil that's just starting to get
up to
temperature we're going to take a bowl
cut the strawberries in half put them in
there because what we're going to do is
add
or quarter depending on how big the
strawberry is we're going to add in some
sugar and the
sugar it will actually bring the water
out of the
strawberries and then that that will
concentrate the flavor make sure you got
a really nice
strong strawberry a is
just another word for
sauce if you're fancy it's a if
you're like me it's a
sauce call it what you like you're
making strawberry jam that's not set
properly nice it's coming up to
temperature nicely we're going to add in
our sugar so here we
go we need 100 g of sugar in
here
or change kilos if you like thanks
scales 1/10th of a kilo we're going to
add that over our strawberries get a
spoon or just this knife that's fine and
just get that all mixed in you do need
that
sugar if you're thinking can I not put
as much sugar in this you you can yeah
you don't have to use this much sugar in
your strawberries but your strawberry
sauce will go icy we're coming to the
end of the temperature raise so I'll get
it up to temperature and then bring it
back over here so you can see me deal
with it good do so our cheesecake base
is ready you'll probably find cuz this
is a high fat recipe that the cream
cheese will settle to the top but that
is
okay because we're going to mix it back
in
after it's chilled
so I'm going
to give that a nice
stir and that is going to go in the
fridge
overnight
Ikea strawberries so they've just been
setting here here for
probably 5 6 minutes something like that
we're going to put all of those in
there we
want all of that Sugar out of there
too and we're going to pop this on the
hob and bring up to temperature get all
of those mated down into a strong
flavored strawberry
and while the strawberries are
doing their thing on here this is going
to take probably
15 to 20 minutes to come
down just let it tick over we're going
to deal with
our cheesecake crumb now in the previous
video that I did yesterday I used theast
digestive biscuits which is what is
available in England I also did the
honey graham cracker
version
and I was hard on the ground cracker
version to start with but after sitting
in the fridge overnight it turned out
infinitely better than this one so we're
going to go with the the gr cracker
version all right and it's going to look
really wet once it comes out of the oven
it's not going to set so you need to
make this ahead of time the same time
you make your base cuz it's going to
need hours in the fridge to set properly
but what you're going to be left with is
a really
buttery crumbly chewy cheesecake base
that we can cut up and put in our ice
cream so that's what we're going to do
sorry mcvities you had your time
Graham's In Charge now so what do we
need for this we we're going to need
butter and our biscuit base so we need
85 G of butter that's probably about
there close
enough GRS of butter and we're want to
melt this in the microwave short stints
don't over melt
it and by over melt and by don't over
melt it I mean don't burn it and we're
going to use up the rest of this we want
[Applause]
G periodically stir your strawberries
don't just let them sit there you'll see
that you'll get loads of liquid come out
and lots of big lumps of strawberry just
leave it ticking over and eventually
those strawberries will break down
so 28
G what did I say 140
G 140
G these are just called Graham
crumbs is there a difference between
Graham crumb and honey Graham crumb I
don't know maybe one's got honey in and
we need some sugar in this as well so
we're going to pop up it's 15 g of
sugar okay get one of those don't need
those
anymore quick brush
down and we're going to bring our oven
up to 360
f
[Music]
and I'm going to change the battery on
the
camera okay the strawberries are not too
far away what I've done is I've got a
small little baking pan lined it with
some
parchment doesn't really matter what
size pan you use for this these are
really nice thick strong ones um they
don't buckle and bend in the oven but
just you're going to cut it up you just
get it nice and flat and get it in the
oven I'd say the thinner the layer then
the less time the oven you don't need to
bake this long so we're just going to
mix up our sugar and
our gram cracker add in our melted
butter and give that a nice stir and it
be very very
liquid
this this base you and you'll look at it
and oh my god that's way too much butter
now if you're making a cheesecake yes it
probably is because it will
start you know traveling in down the or
it will spread in your thing you know in
your pan but you actually kind of want
that
here so we're going to get a
spoon which I don't
have spoon let me get our spoon
and get it all in there press it down
press it out
flat we're not making masses of this
stuff here it goes quite a long
way but try and get the thickness even
if you
can and then we have a very buttery
graham cracker and we're going to wait 2
minutes whil the oven heats up and then
we're going to pop it in for 10 minutes
only okay we're just going to take the
strawberries off the
heat and just let it cool down a bit
because we're going to push all those
super soft lumps of strawberries through
a fine mesh save into a pot to cool down
completely okay so ovens up temperature
we're going to pop this in so just as a
reminder this cheesecake crumb is going
in a 360 fenhe oven for 10 minutes
now whilst that's doing that we're going
to
strain our
[Music]
strawberries through
here and then we'll just pop that in
there and that's it that's our
strawberry sauce done we're going to pop
it into a smaller
container and let that thicken up in the
fridge now in the first video I added
lemon juice to this to help the
structure of the pectin or to help the
pectin form the structure it needs to to
set the jam you don't need to add it but
we're going to test and see if this sets
up as much as I need it to if it doesn't
we'll deal with it another way we'll
deal with it a scientific way so LD on
in the fridge
overnight the Crum is out of the oven
that's it we're going to leave it here
to comp completely cool down get it down
to room temperature and then we're going
to pop it in this container in the
fridge overnight with everything else
and then we'll come back
tomorrow okay something to note and I
think I mentioned it earlier when making
the strawberry sauce but if not I'll
mention it again I ran out of lemon
juice
um lemon juice so this is the first
strawberry from the first
variation of this this which you didn't
see thicker this that had lemon juice in
this doesn't have lemon juice and as you
can see it's much much thinner okay so I
ran out of lemon juice I'm not going to
go out and buy some more so what we're
going to do is we're going to thicken
this with
science okay so we're going to take our
zanam gum zanon gum Go gum both hydrate
cold uh that means you can as long as
you can disperse it properly within your
liquid you can thicken something pretty
quickly so we're going to
take a tiny little bit of
sugar you like my uh my sugar
bowl we're going to take a tiny little
bit of sugar we don't want too much
because we don't need any more sugar in
this but we need to disperse the zanth
gum and into
that
I'm not even going to weigh this cuz
it's not really that important
but I'm going to take an eighth of a
teaspoon okay eighth of a teaspoon
is about half a gram something like that
all right and we've got it in there so
there's not a lot in there we're just
going to swirl this around we're going
to distribute that xantham gum within
the sugar and we're going to add it into
this so remember what this look like
okay very
thin cold it's been in the fridge all
night and we're going to try and thicken
this
up with
that
okay I want my little
whisk where's my mini whisk there's a
mini whisk this will do and here we go
stir it
in we're going to keep
stirring and make sure that zanam gum
gets
completely dissolved and we'll see if
that helps us thicken it up okay it's
already starting to thicken it up after
just a couple of minutes all right I did
add just a touch more so another 1/4
teaspoon in another you know half
teaspoon of sugar mix that up mix that
back in now in theory that should do the
job nicely we're going to sit that
side we're going to use the stuff from
yesterday waste not whatnot and all that
oh look
strawberry so what's left to do now turn
the ice cream get it in the tub so let's
get the ice cream machine out get it
ched down and then I'll come back and
load it all up right we've ched the
machine down for 10 minutes something
like that and we've taken our base out
giv it a good whisk make sure
everything's Incorporated high fat
recipe so you'll get some sat sat fation
that's what you're going to
get you're going to get some fat
separation um whisk it back in don't
worry about it just whisk it back in
make sure it's really nicely combined
again before you put it in your ice
cream machine it will all come together
I promise okay so let's load this
up and get it
[Music]
churning and whilst that's churning
we're going to take our graham cracker
this is the stuff from the previous
video left over it's I have been eating
it I'm not going to lie it's is so much
better than I thought it was going to be
M
good we're going to chop it up into nice
little cubes this is new stuff and chop
all chop it all up into nice little
cubes and get it ready for loading up
time because we're stirring in the
biscuit base and the strawberry sauce
we're going to stop the churn just a
couple of minutes early it really helps
if the ice cream is a little bit thinner
to fold the ingredients in if you make
it and churn it right up to the end of
the churn time then when you add in some
of the ingredients they just disappear
or break apart because the ice cream
causes too much friction with your
biscuit base or whatever it is so that's
why I like to if there's lots of addins
just take it out a couple of minutes
early now it's time to load the DS
it's the next day let's get some of this
dished up in a
bowl see what it turned out like
[Music]
again
so as a high fat recipe you will likely
need to take this out of the freezer for
a few minutes um you can counteract that
again with a sugar Dex Rose combination
dropping some of the suit Crow down
adding dextr or make it softer and
easier to scoop but it's a game that
sometimes is just not worth playing for
high fat recipes it's the added fat that
makes it slightly harder but along with
that as it melts you get this Ultra
creamy texture so you can see we got our
strawberry Ripple going through there we
got our lovely pieces of Cheesecake base
let's
see what it's
like so
good super creamy not
fatty there's no fatty drag on the spoon
and your mouth really really nice Ultra
nice mouth feel just flavor
lingers you get that strawberry swirl
come through in the big pockets of the
strawberry it will turn a little bit icy
you can counter that with more sugar
strangely enough but I don't think you
need to win this it's tart it's tart
enough to cut through that fatty ice
cream as well and with
the super
buttery gray cracker cheesecake
base so
[Music]
good my wife rated this one is in her
top
five last night when we were sat down
watching a movie so praise enough just
there but if you're in doubt give this
one a try you will not be disappointed
don't worry too much about the fat
content it's worth in the end anyway
thanks very much for watching and
following don't forget to like And
subscribe if you if you have not
subscribed so far big thank you to my
Kofi supporters I'll put a list on the
screen sideways here they really really
help me buy all these unique ingredients
so I mean there's a lot involved in this
ice
cream so all the support I get from all
of you is massively appreciated thank
you ever so much again and I will see
you next week when it's chocolate series
episode